## resume

# John Leidegren

john@leidegren.se 0734 304 638

#### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with a passion for technology. More than 5 years of professional experience on desktop, web and mobile platforms. A strong sense for technology in general and game development. Team player, driven by ambitious goals and a creative mindset.

I write a lot of code, not because I have to, but because to write code, is to me like a moth to a flame, inseparable. I'm a diverse programmer but value a profound understanding of how things work. Correctness is rather important to me, and I don't do guess work. I want predictable results, and get 'em by relying on **SOLID** principles. I prototype and I test because I make mistakes, but I rather work hard and *fail often to succeed sooner*.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Software Engineer

# **SNOW SOFTWARE**

May 2011 - Current

I go where the product takes me, both involved in design and testing. I've written everything from Windows software kernel-mode drivers, to web applications that deal with asynchronous workflows. I've built a public key infrastructure for handling different licensing schemes and setup build/continuous integration environments.

I also develop and maintain a lightweight agent that deals with software and hardware inventory on a multitude of platforms. This agent runs on millions of Windows PCs worldwide.

## Software Engineer

# **MIRA NETWORK**

April 2009 - April 2011

\_

# Internship EA DICE

## **ELECTRONIC ARTS**

September 2008 - January 2009

Identified network bottlenecks by instrumenting and profiling the Frostbite game engine. Presented a solution on how to improve bandwidth utilization by relying on a history of previously transmitted data, while being efficient about memory usage.

## **EDUCATION**

## **MSC COMPUTER SCIENCE**

2004 - 2009

Also, mentor for academic tutoring program that targets historically difficult courses so as to improve student performance by offering regularly scheduled, out-of-class sessions.

## **SKILLS**

- Fluent in C/C++, C# and JavaScript.
- Good with asynchronous computing.
- Excellent understanding of concurrency and hardware parallelism.
- Functional programming (Haskell, lambdas, immutable objects, monads, LINQ).
- Solid understanding of software engineering principles (SOLID, DRY, KISS)<sup>1</sup> and best practices.
- Excellent with data structures and analysis of algorithms.
- Knowledgeable about utilizing CPU/GPU hardware for performance gains.
- Networking with TCP/IP and UDP protocols.
- Solid understanding of Web technologies (HTML/CSS, jQuery, HTTP and RESTful services).
- Many years of professional experience with the .NET platform, 4.0/4.5 (XAML/WPF/WCF).
- Experience working with and optimizing Microsoft SQL Server.
- Experience developing user interface flows and mockups based on project requirements.
- Knowledgeable with content authoring tools such as Adobe Photoshop, Autodesk 3ds Max, Autodesk Maya and Blender.

## **SOFT SKILLS**

- Curious and creative personality.
- Comfortable dealing with and learning from mistakes.
- Big appetite for learning new things.
- Keen interest into all things game development.
- Knowledge of various SDLC methodologies (waterfall, agile, SCRUM).

## **INTERESTS**

- Computer science
- Concept art and design
- Games
- Guitars

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>1</sup> Pun intended, but I also believe that these principles can have a profound impact on how we create software.